CHRISTINE LE

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I am a Software Engineer with experience in health tech, passionate about making tech accessible to all. My careful analytical skills and empathic understanding of my clients' needs enable me to merge efficiency and usability in the products I create. In each project, I seek to connect the needs of businesses and consumers, using data to help them feel more confident in their decision making. Whether in a group or individually, I am both detailfocused and adaptable, which helps me anticipate and solve challenges while remaining flexible to changing circumstances.

SKILLS

Languages

Java · JavaScript · Python · HTML · CSS

Frameworks / Libraries

Spring Boot · React · PostgreSQL · MongoDB · Pandas · Mocha & Chai · JUnit · Jest

Methodologies

Test Driven Development · Unit Testing · Version Control & Git · Responsive Design · OOP · CRUD · AJAX · RESTful API

Tools

AWS EC2 & S3 · Docker · Kubernetes · Heroku · Atlassian JIRA & Confluence · Figma

Bioinformatics Applications

 $\mbox{BioPython} \cdot \mbox{BLAST} \cdot \mbox{KEGG} \cdot \mbox{Reactome} \cdot \mbox{BioGrid} \cdot \\ \mbox{OMIM} \cdot \mbox{STRING}$

EDUCATION

City University of New York, Hunter College, New York, NY

- Bachelor of Arts in Biology, Concentration in Bioinformatics
- December 2018

CONTACT

Mobile: 646-945-0115 Email: christine.le244@gmail.com Website: christinele.nyc Github: @le-christine LinkedIn: @christinele3

PROJECTS

Community Cares

- https://github.com/le-christine/community-cares
- Based on a user's query, this tool delivers information about free programs and benefits in New York City
- Spring Boot / PostgreSQL / React

Tea Room

- https://github.com/le-christine/tea-room
- A reddit-like clone where users can make posts and comments
- Spring Boot / PostgreSQL / HTML / CSS / JavaScript

Pixel Art

- http://christinele.nyc/pixelart/
- This pixel art drawing tool features a color palette to hold a user's favorite or most used color swatches
- HTML / CSS / JavaScript

EXPERIENCE

American Express Developer Academy

General Assembly, New York, NY | August 2019 - Present

- Develop script to Create-Read-Update-Delete products from database using frameworks such as Spring Boot and PostgreSQL, AJAX, and RESTful API
- Design reusable pure components and responsive features using React.js, Redux, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap
- Pair program and experience Agile software development methodologies through working on multiple teams to plan, build and review code
- Maintain industry best practices with clear code documentation, git, and test-driven development

Bioinformatics Associate

Celmatix, New York, NY | June 2018 - August 2019

- Applied proprietary scoring system to identify genes as potential drug targets for complex reproductive disorders
- Constructed pathway analysis tools to rank gene target prioritization
- Redesigned database that automatically interprets data from literature curation, reducing the data processing time by 20%
- Built presentations to forge pharmaceutical partnerships and highlight key selling points of drug target identification strategy
- Presented 2 weekly summaries of relevant scientific research to Bioinformatics team to support the company's projects

Computer Lab Assistant

Hunter College, New York, NY | August 2017 - June 2018

- Diagnosed and resolved student-reported computer problems
- Installed and maintained computer laboratory hardware and software

Pharmacy Technician

Rite Aid Pharmacy, College Point, NY | September 2015- February 2016

- Ensured compliance with HIPPA regulations by prioritizing patient privacy and properly disposing medication labels and documents
- Interacted with and supported chronically ill patients visiting the pharmacy